# Cumhur AKKAYA DEVOPS ENGINEER

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/cumhur-akkaya-0108b1248 Address: Çanakkale, Turkey

GitHub: github.com/cmakkaya

#### **SUMMARY**

+3 years of experience in IT Project Management. Passionate about automation of IT processes. HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate. AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner. Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA). Expert in designing and building effective **Continuous Integration and Delivery (CI/CD) pipelines** using **containerization**, **orchestration**, **monitoring**, infrastructure automation tools, configuration management tools, and **AWS** solutions. To be able to use **Jira** as a project management tool and agile methodology as a project management method. Highly adaptable, flexible professional who embraces teamwork but also likes to work independently. Armed with remarkable problem solving, multitasking, and time management abilities.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Clarusway - Mentor July 2022 - Present

UME - IT and Security Project Manager April 2012- February 2015

HERİKKS and SENTİNEL System - Trainer August 2005 – December 2011

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python | SQL | Linux | Git | GitHub | Cloud(AWS) | CloudFormation | EC2 | ECR | DynamoDB | CloudFront | S3 | API GW | Lambda | EFS | Boto3 | CloudWatch | RDS | MariaDB | ALB with ASG | Apache | Nginx | Snapshots | Volumes | VPC | Route53 | Certificate Manager | IAM | AMI | Jenkins | Docker | Kubernetes | Jira | ClickUp | Slack | Ansible | Terraform | Scrum/Kanban

### **SOFT SKILLS**

Teamwork | Team Management | Problem Solving | Continuous Learning | Creativity | Time Management | Focus | Computational Thinking | Communication | Leadership | Collaboration | Adaptability | Self Motivation

#### **PROJECTS**

- Web Page Application (Postgresql-Nodejs-React) deployed on EC2's with Ansible, Docker, and Nginx Proxy Server.
- Microservice Architecture for Web Application with MySQL using Kubernetes.
- Jenkins Pipeline for Dockerized Application Deployed on Docker Swarm.
- Dockerization of Web API with MySql.
- An application deployed on AWS Application Load Balancer with Auto Scaling and RDS using Terraform.
- Create **Apache** Servers with Terraform.
- An Application (Django) deployed on AWS Application Load Balancer with Auto Scaling, S3, RDS, VPC's Components, Lambda, DynamoDB, and Cloudfront with Route53.
- Static Website deployed on **AWS Cloudfront**, S3, and Route53 using Cloudformation.

## **AWS Hands-On Experience on:**

• EC2, CloudFormation, ECR, DynamoDB, CloudFront, S3, API GW, Lambda, EFS, Boto3, CloudWatch, RDS, MariaDB, ALB with ASG, Apache, Nginx, Snapshots, Volumes, VPC, WordPress, Route53, Certificate Manager, IAM, AMI.

## **DevOps Hands-On Experience on:**

- **Docker:** Installing basic operations, handling volumes, networking, image basic operations, composing operations, dockerize to-do app on python-flask, swarm basic operations, swarm network managing services, secrets, tasks.
- **Kubernetes:** Installing and basic operations, networking service discovery, Microservice deployment, and auto-scaling, managing secrets and config maps, pods and volumes, managing Kubernetes cluster with EKS, dynamic volume provisioning, and ingress.
- Ansible: Using modules with ad-hoc commands, using playbooks with tasks, using secrets, provisioning a web and DB server with dynamic websites, working with dynamic inventory, using roles.
- **Jenkins:** Installing, building Jenkins job, building Jenkins pipeline, installing and configuring tomcat, deployment to the staging environment, building pipeline with docker ECR.
- Terraform: Installing Terraform and building AWS infrastructure with Terraform.
- Nexus: Installing and using Proxy Repository on EC2 Instance.

## **EDUCATION**

# Gebze Technical University,

Jul 2015 -

Doctorate, Business Administration, Grade: 3,81. I took a break at the thesis stage.

Istanbul University, Oct 2014 - Jul 2020

Bachelor, Sociology, Grade: 3,7.

## **Necmettin Erbakan University**

Oct 2010 - Jun 2012

Master's Degree, Guidance and Psychological Counseling (GDC), Grade: 81.08.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Clarusway AWS/DevOps Course Certification.
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner.
- HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate.
- Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA).

## LANGUAGES:

Turkish : Native

English : Advanced

Arabic : Elementary